<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="paullou.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="paullou.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-10T23:00:53+00:00</updated><id>paullou.me/blog/</id><title type="html">plou’s tHoTFuL SPot</title><subtitle>thoughts, endeavors, and ramblings</subtitle><author><name>Paul S. Lou</name></author><entry><title type="html">appreciating oatmeal</title><link href="paullou.me/blog/thoughts/2019/03/10/oatmeal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="appreciating oatmeal" /><published>2019-03-10T18:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-10T18:14:00+00:00</updated><id>paullou.me/blog/thoughts/2019/03/10/oatmeal</id><content type="html" xml:base="paullou.me/blog/thoughts/2019/03/10/oatmeal/">&lt;p&gt;Steel-cut oats, Scottish oats, old-fashioned rolled oats, quick-oats, and oat bran. 
These are my morning ingredients for sustained energy and discipline.
Oatmeal is to me as shrimp is to Bubba from Forrest Gump.
If shrimp is like the fruit of the sea, oatmeal is the meal of the oats of the
land… right, not quite sure what I was going for there.
Plain oats will do just fine, but we can make oats with bananas, cinnamon and brown sugar,
peanut butter, jam, coconut flakes, almond slices, and eggs.
There’s overnight oats, slow-cooked oats, microwaved oats, and uncooked oats.
Considering the set of adjectives one could prefix and suffix to oats or oatmeal
we have a large finite set of potential oatmeals that I hope to explore in the
coming mornings.
Tea-steeped overnight oats… espresso-steeped overnight oats… tiramisu 
with overnight oats… not-overnight overnight oats?
Let’s be real: I microwave and eat the same oatmeal recipe every morning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Paul S. Lou</name></author><summary type="html">Steel-cut oats, Scottish oats, old-fashioned rolled oats, quick-oats, and oat bran. These are my morning ingredients for sustained energy and discipline. Oatmeal is to me as shrimp is to Bubba from Forrest Gump. If shrimp is like the fruit of the sea, oatmeal is the meal of the oats of the land… right, not quite sure what I was going for there. Plain oats will do just fine, but we can make oats with bananas, cinnamon and brown sugar, peanut butter, jam, coconut flakes, almond slices, and eggs. There’s overnight oats, slow-cooked oats, microwaved oats, and uncooked oats. Considering the set of adjectives one could prefix and suffix to oats or oatmeal we have a large finite set of potential oatmeals that I hope to explore in the coming mornings. Tea-steeped overnight oats… espresso-steeped overnight oats… tiramisu with overnight oats… not-overnight overnight oats? Let’s be real: I microwave and eat the same oatmeal recipe every morning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">lunch times</title><link href="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/27/lunch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="lunch times" /><published>2017-05-27T23:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-27T23:30:00+00:00</updated><id>paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/27/lunch</id><content type="html" xml:base="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/27/lunch/">&lt;p&gt;In my book, there are only three times to eat lunch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Around 11:00 before lines form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After 2:30 in the afternoon to avoid lines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or don’t eat lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Paul S. Lou</name></author><summary type="html">In my book, there are only three times to eat lunch: Around 11:00 before lines form. After 2:30 in the afternoon to avoid lines. Or don’t eat lunch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">bike-tastrophe</title><link href="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/26/biketastrophe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="bike-tastrophe" /><published>2017-05-26T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-26T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/26/biketastrophe</id><content type="html" xml:base="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/26/biketastrophe/">&lt;p&gt;So I stopped at this redlight on my “new” bike and I noticed that although I
stopped, the front wheel was still rolling a little forward. Out of curiousity,
I picked up my bike by the handles to understand what had just happend. 
Lo and behold, it turns out my front wheel detached itself off the fork. Welp.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Paul S. Lou</name></author><summary type="html">So I stopped at this redlight on my “new” bike and I noticed that although I stopped, the front wheel was still rolling a little forward. Out of curiousity, I picked up my bike by the handles to understand what had just happend. Lo and behold, it turns out my front wheel detached itself off the fork. Welp.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">finished bike</title><link href="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/22/bike-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="finished bike" /><published>2017-05-22T01:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-22T01:30:00+00:00</updated><id>paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/22/bike-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/22/bike-work/">&lt;p&gt;So here are the photos. These are the tools and the new bike levers:
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/seattle-jank-bike/tools.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tools&quot; /&gt;
And these are the old bike handles:
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/seattle-jank-bike/old_bike_handles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Old Bike Handles&quot; /&gt;
The calipers you see below are centerpull brake calipers. 
My fingers were crying and my back was mad aching by the end
of servicing them. I had to take multiple tries adjusting the break cable
in the yolk and I inadvertently looped the rear break cable onto the nut for the 
seat height adjustment. So I can’t actually adjust the seat height anymore…
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/seattle-jank-bike/front_calipers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front Calipers&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/seattle-jank-bike/rear_calipers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rear Calipers&quot; /&gt;
This is what the bike looked like after I was done:
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/seattle-jank-bike/finished_prod.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finished&quot; /&gt;
And I took it down a slope to test the breaks:
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/seattle-jank-bike/test_slope.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Slope&quot; /&gt;
The breaks were weak but acceptable since I can use my feet to stop
myself after slowing down enough. So YAY!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Paul S. Lou</name></author><summary type="html">So here are the photos. These are the tools and the new bike levers: And these are the old bike handles: The calipers you see below are centerpull brake calipers. My fingers were crying and my back was mad aching by the end of servicing them. I had to take multiple tries adjusting the break cable in the yolk and I inadvertently looped the rear break cable onto the nut for the seat height adjustment. So I can’t actually adjust the seat height anymore… This is what the bike looked like after I was done: And I took it down a slope to test the breaks: The breaks were weak but acceptable since I can use my feet to stop myself after slowing down enough. So YAY!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">plan: replacing bike levers</title><link href="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/19/bike-levers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="plan: replacing bike levers" /><published>2017-05-19T15:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-19T15:30:00+00:00</updated><id>paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/19/bike-levers</id><content type="html" xml:base="paullou.me/blog/seattle/2017/05/19/bike-levers/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been pretty excited for a while to get a vintage
roadbike and I finally bought one in Seattle off Craigslist for $60 cash. I’ll
attach a photo sometime, but the bike is in fair condition with just a slight
bit of rust. The most enjoyable yet concerning features are the downtube shifters
and the fact that I can’t really grip/reach the break levers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downtube gear shifters are RETRO. Together with drinking Seattle cold brew, using downtube
shifters feels really hipster.
Unfortunately, these shifters are slightly less convenient because of where they are
located on the bike: down on the frame rather than where the hands sit on the
handlebars. I’m glad they work because I’m not sure it’s possible to bike
Seattle without multi-speed bikes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about this bike are its almost unreachable break levers. And
this would be totally okay if it weren’t for the Seattle streets. As I walked to
work the first day from Capitol Hill to Downtown, I discovered to my surprise that
Seattle has streets that
roll up and down. They are reminiscent of San Francisco’s to a
lesser degree. As someone trying to ride a vintage bike with downtube
shifters, it’s daunting enough to think about going uphill on varying inclines. But as someone
trying to ride a vintage bike with unreachable break levers, downhill sounds just
FANTASTIC. So here’s the upcoming weekend project. I spent about about $11 on a new set
of break cables and housing, and another $16 on break levers which arrive
tomorrow. I’m going to manually install responsive break levers. Photos to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Paul S. Lou</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been pretty excited for a while to get a vintage roadbike and I finally bought one in Seattle off Craigslist for $60 cash. I’ll attach a photo sometime, but the bike is in fair condition with just a slight bit of rust. The most enjoyable yet concerning features are the downtube shifters and the fact that I can’t really grip/reach the break levers.</summary></entry></feed>